Guide to the Cornell University Center for Aerial Photographic Studies records,.
Cornell University Center for Aerial Photographic Studies records
- Series III. Additional Roll Film and Documents
  - Subseries III k. New York State Lakes
    - Flight summary reports for 72-169, 72-181, 73-046A, 73-014B, 73-041, 73-085A, 73-160, 74-016, 74-033, 74-060A, 74-080A, 74-080B, 74-081B, 74-119, and 74-124, 1972-1974 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Flight summary report and drawn maps of flight 75-055A, 1975 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Flight 73-160 roll film, September, 1973 (Box 20)
      Southwest New York, Northwest Pennsylvania
    - Flight 72-145 roll film, August, 1972 (Box 20)
      Lake Ontario, Lake Champlain, Northeast US
    - Flight 73-065 roll film, April, 1973 (Box 21)
      Hudson Valley
    - Flight 74-081B roll film, May, 1974 (Box 21)
      Lake Champlain, Northeast Adirondacks
    - Flight 74-80B roll film, May, 1974 (Box 21)
      Buffalo, Niagara
    - Flight 73-041 roll film, March, 1973 (Box 22)
      Ontario, Erie, Central New York
    - Flight 73-055A roll film, May, 1975 (Box 22)
    - Roll unnumbered, October, 1974 (Box 22)
      Syracuse/Cortland
    - Flight 74-081B roll film, May, 1974 (Box 22)
  - Subseries III l. Texas VI
    - Houston Area, November, 1971 (Box 24)
    - Mississippi, two reels, November, 1971 (Box 24)
    - Northeast Gulf of Mexico, November, 1971 (Box 24)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority, November, 1971 (Box 24)
    - Sam Houston National Forest, 3 reels, November, 1971 (Box 25)
    - Mississippi Sound, November, 1971 (Box 25)
    - Houston Area, November, 1971 (Box 25)
  - Subseries III m. Texas VII
    - Trinity Bay, two reels, 1972 (Box 23)
    - Sam Houston National Forest, November, 1971 (Box 26)
    - San Antonio Bay, two reels, February, 1972 (Box 26)
    - San Antonio Bay, January, 1972 (Box 26)
    - Trinity Bay, five reels, February, 1972 (Box 27)
    - San Antonio Bay, three reels, February, 1972 (Box 28)
    - San Antonio Bay, January, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Houston Area, April, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Big Spring, Texas, two reels, April, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Black Mesa, Arizona, two reels, April, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Phoenix, Arizona, April, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Big Spring, Texas, two reels, April, 1972 (Box 29)
    - Houston Area, January, 1972 (Box 29)
  - Subseries III n. High Altitude mission 4
    - Unlabelled, July, 1969 (Box 23)
    - Gila River and Bucks Lake, California, July, 1969 (Box 31)
    - Imperial Valley, California, July, 1969 (Box 31)
    - Southern Arizona, July, 1969 (Box 31)
    - Santa Barbara, Imperial Valley, Southern Arizona, March, 1969 (Box 31)
  - Subseries III o. Unknown missions
    - Finger Lakes, Flight 73-085A, June, 1973 (Box 19)
    - Aquatic Vegetation, Cayuga and Seneca Lakes, September, 1968 (Box 19)
    - Northern New York, January, 1971 (Box 19)
    - Seasat SAR 1339, 1981 (Box 29)
    - Suntrana (Box 29)
    - Mm 2 1-53 (Box 30)
    - Alaska Airport, Yukon Delta, Permafrost (Box 30)
    - Montezuma (Box 30)
    - Watertown, New York (Box 30)
    - M10-2L-1.5-4032 (Box 30)
    - Canadarago Lake, August, 1976 (Box 30)
    - Unidentified, two reels (Box 30)
    - Grapevines, two reels, 1980 (Box 23)
- Series IV. Landforms
  - Volume I, bound original, 1951 (Box 37)
    I. Drainage Analysis
    II. Gully Analysis
    III. Vegetation Analysis
    IV. Tone Analysis
  - Volume II, bound original, 1951 (Box 37)
    Chapter 1: Sec. 1 Sandstone
    Sec. 2 Shale
    Sec. 3A Limestone
    Sec. 3B Limestone (Tropical Karst)
    Sec. 4 Coral
    Sec. 5A Interbedded Sedimentary Rocks (Flat-lying)
    Sec. 5B Interbedded Sedimentary Rocks (Tilted)
  - Volume III, bound original, 1951 (Box 37)
    Chapter 2: Igneous Rock
    Introduction
    Sec. 1 Intrusive Rocks (Granite and related rocks)
    Sec. 2A Extrusive Rocks (Basaltic Lava)
    Sec. 2B Extrusive Rocks (Fragmental and related intebedded flows)
    Sec. 3 Miscellaneous features
  - Volume III, bound original, 1951 (Box 37)
    Chapter 3: Metamorphic Rocks
    Sec. 1 Gneiss
    Sec. 2 Schist
    Sec. 3 Slate
    Sec. 4 Serpentine
  - Volume IV, bound original, 1951 (Box 37)
    Chapter 4: Waterlaid Materials
    Sec. 1 Flood plains
    Sec. 2 Terraces
    Sec. 3 Filled Valley
    Sec. 4 Continental Alluvium
    Sec. 5 Alluvial Fans
    Sec. 6 Deltas
    Sec. 7 Lake Beds
    Sec. 8 Beach Ridges
    Sec. 9 Coastal Plains
    Sec. 10 Tidal Flats
    Sec. 11 Marshes and Swamps
  - Volume V, bound original, 1951 (Box 37)
    Chapter 5: Glacial Materials
    Sec. 1 Eskers
    Sec. 2 Kames
    Sec. 3 Outwash Plains
    Sec. 4 Terraces
    Sec. 5 Lake Beds
    Sec. 6 Till Plains
    Sec. 7 Moraines
    Sec. 8 Drumlins
    Sec. 9 Complex Glacial Deposits
  - Volume VI, bound original, 1951 (Box 37)
    Chapter 6: Windlaid Materials
    Sec. 1 Sand Dunes
    Sec. 2 Loess
  - Bound copies of volumes I-VI, volume V in a binder, 1951 (Box 37)
  - Volume II and III, in binders, 1951 (Box 38)
  - Volume IV and V, in binders, 1951 (Box 39)
  - Volume VI, in binder, 1951 (Box 40)
  - Beach Report binder, 1951 (Box 40)
  - Granites de Vengochla binder (Box 40)
  - Additional Material binder (Box 40)
  - Loose copies of Landform reports and instruction sheet (Box 41, Folder 1-6)
  - Loose copies of Landform reports with corresponding loose photographs (Box 41, Folder 7-14)
- Series V. Documents and Publications
  Many belonged to Ta Liang.
  - Subseries V a. General
    - Landform and terrain analysis manuals and studies, southeast Asia, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Landform and terrain analysis manuals and studies, United States, 1968, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Forestry booklets, 1956-1984 (Box 42, Folder 3-5, 12)
    - Airphoto analysis and interpretation manuals, 1960-1968 (Box 42, Folder 6-8)
    - Airphoto analysis of Taiwan (Box 42, Folder 9-10)
    - Inventory of aerial photography and other remotely sensed imagery of New York State, 1975, 1979 (Box 43, Folder 8-9, 12)
    - "Instruction Manual Vertical Sketchmaster, Type 260GE" (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - "Aerial photographs in the National Archives", 1973 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - "Detailed land classification: Island of Hawaii", 1965 (Box 43)
    - "Terrain Study of the Panama Canal Zone," with maps, July, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - "Geology and Paleontology of Canal Zone and Adjoining Parts of Panama", 1982 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - "ERTS-1: A New Window on Our Planet", 1976 (Box 46)
    - NASA "Earth Photographs from Gemini II, IV, and V", 1967 (Box 46)
    - NASA "Earth Photographs from Gemini VI through VII", 1968 (Box 46)
    - NASA "Exploring Space with a Camera", 1968 (Box 46)
    - NASA "Skylab: Explores the Earth", 1977 (Box 46)
    - NASA "Skylab: EREP Investigations Summary", 1978 (Box 46)
    - NASA "Analysis of Apollo 8 Photography and Visual Observations" (Box 46)
    - Status of Aerial Photography map, June, 1966 (Box 46)
    - "Inventario Cafeeiro", 1968 (Box 48)
    - Niagara preliminary results, 1978 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - "Ground Water in the Niagara Falls Area, New York", 1964 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Map of Erie County and Love Canal (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Xenix PC/AT Backup Procedures (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Niagara Site Conditions (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - "Aerial Photography and Photogrammetry in the Coast and Geodetic Survey", 1964 (Box 50, Folder 37)
    - Map of the Bahamas (Box 50, Folder 38)
    - "The Landsat Tutorial Workbook" (Box 50)
    - "Multispectral Photography for Earth Resources", 1972 (Box 50)
    - "Photographic Interpretation Keys: Indochina", 1970 (Box 50)
    - "Color Aerial Stereograms of Selected Coastal Areas of the United States", 1971 (Box 50)
    - "Transactions of the Symposium on Photo Interpretation", 1963 (Box 50)
    - "Manual of Coastal Delineation from Aerial Photographs", 1947 (Box 50)
    - "The Uses of Air Photography: Nature and Man in a New Perspective", 1965 (Box 50)
    - "Elements of Photogrammetry", 1983 (Box 50)
    - "Regional Master Plan Studies: Andros in the Bahamas", 1959 (Box 52)
    - "Airphoto Interpretation and the Canadian Landscape", 1983 (Box 52)
    - "People's Republic of China Atlas, CIA", 1971 (Box 52)
    - NASA, "Arctic and Antarctic Sea Ice, 1978-1987", 1992 (Box 53)
    - "Photographic Interpretation Keys: Coastal Zones of the Mediterranean Basin", 1957 (Box 53)
    - "Earth-Science Maps Applied to Land and Water Management", 1978 (Box 53)
    - "Allied Geographical Section, Southwest Pacific Area, Terrain Study No 101 Panay: Philippine Series", 1944 (Box 53)
    - "Military Engineering Experimental Establishment Christchurch, Report III Vol 2", 1971 (Box 54)
    - Mollard, "Landforms and landscapes of Canada" (Box 54)
  - Subseries V b. Cornell Publications and Reports, Published in Ithaca
    - Airphoto Analysis of Land Forms: Union of Burma, volume 3, 1955 (Box 44)
    - Airphoto Analysis of Forestry: Union of Burma, two copies of volume 2, 1955 (Box 44)
    - Airphoto Analysis of Regional and Urban Planning: Union of Burma, volume 3, 1955 (Box 44)
    - Environmental Analysis of the Fort Churchill, Manitoba region, 1955 (Box 44)
    - Mariner Photography of Mars and Aerial Photography of Earth: Some Analogies, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Typed volume on glacial land forms (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - The Center for Aerial Photographic Studies publications on land use, 1967, 1971 (Box 45, Folder 3-6)
    - Camp Cornell short course on location and evaluation of gravel sources for highway use, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Tropical Soils: Characteristics and Airphoto Interpretation, two copies, August 31, 1964 (Box 45, Folder 7-9)
    - Research Investigation into Factors Affecting Long Range Photography, 1954 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Determination of Beach Conditions by Means of Aerial Photographic Interpretation, two copies of Volume II, June, 1954 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Determination of Beach Conditions by Means of Aerial Photographic Interpretation, two copies of Volume IV, June, 1954 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Determination of Beach Conditions by Means of Aerial Photographic Interpretation, two copies of Volume V, June, 1954 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Donald Belcher and Associates, "A Technical Report: Selection of the Five Sites Most Favorable for the Location of the New Capital of the United States of Brasil", February, 1955 (Box 48)
  - Subseries V c. Panama Project
    - Panama maps, summary of long-range program for the Panama Canal, 1960 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Maps of Panama, 1960s (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Four aerial photographs of Panama (Box 46)
    - The Penome-Colon Highway: Preliminary Report, Phase A, 1965 (Box 46)
  - Subseries V d. Puerto Rico Project
    - Maps of Puerto Rico, including Metallogenic Map, 1960-1980 (Box 46, Folder 7-11)
    - "Soil Survey Laboratory Data and Descriptions for Some Soils For: Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands", August, 1967 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - "Summary Appraisals of the Nation's Ground-Water Resources: Caribbean Region", 1980 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - "Final Report: An Investigation of On-shore and Off-shore Physical Features of Potential Port Sites, Puerto Rico", three copies, 1960 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - "Geology of the Middle Tertiary Formations of Puerto Rico", 1980 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - "Geology of the Coamo Area, Puerto Rico, and its Relation to the Volcanic Arc-Trench Association", 1971 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - "Environmental Report", 1971 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - "Trafficability Predictions in Tropical Soils: Puerto Rico Study", 1960 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - "The utility of Skylab photo-interpreted earth resources data in studies of marine geology and coastal processes in Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands", 1975 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - "Karst Landforms of Puerto Rico", 1976 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - "Scenic Value in Puerto Rico", 1972 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - "Preliminary Report: Soils Investigation of Potential Port Sites", 1960 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Arecibo Strip maps (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Soil type sheets (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Air photo index (Box 47, Folder 9-10)
    - Correspondence and documents of Ta Liang, 1958 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - "Economic Geology of the Fajardo and Cayo Icacos Quadrangles, Puerto Rico", 1967 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Jack Rinker, "An Application of Air Photo Analysis to a Cave Location Study", 1973 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Air photo notes, Central La Plata (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Air photos, Patillas Quad (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Documents on shore studies (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Air photo index, notes on site selection (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Arecibo documents and reports (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - MONA original photos, 1971-1972 (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Transparent photographs (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Two aerial photographs (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Landsat/Skylab aerial photographs (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Maps and diagrams, some hand drawn (Box 47, Folder 22-24)
    - "Geology of the Ciales Quadrangle, Puerto Rico", 1965 (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - "Geology of the Florida Quadrangle, Puerto Rico", 1966 (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - "Cretaceous and Lower Tertiary Stratigraphy of the Gurabo and El Yunque Quadrangles, Puerto Rico" (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - "Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands", 1980 (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - "Geology of Isla Desecheo, Puerto Rico, with Notes on the Great Southern Puerto Rico Fault Zone and Quaternary Stillstands of the Sea", 1972 (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - "Geology of the Coamo Area, Puerto Rico, and its Relation to the Volcanic Arc-Trench Association", 1971 (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - "Construction Material Resources of the Manati Quadrangle", 1966 (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - Geology of the San Juan Metropolitan Area, Puerto Rico" (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - "Shoreline Features and Quaternary Shoreline Changes, Puerto Rico", 1959 (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - "Climates of the States: Puerto Rico and US Virgin Islands", 1961 (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - "Natural, Cultural and Environmental Resources Inventory" Part I and II, Final Report, 1973 (Box 47, Folder 27)
    - Rafael Pico, "Nueva Geografia de Puerto Rico" (Box 47)
    - Maps and Legends (Box 48, Folder 1)
- Series VI. Photographs, 1950-1986
  Gelatin silver prints
  Chromogenic prints
  Color slides
  Color transparencies
  - Bahamas (Box 41, Folder 15)
    Soils and agricultural possibilities of central and southern Andros Island.
  - Bahamas, 1956-1959 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    Also includes maps, travel brochures, and paper on Andros Island.
  - Denmark (Box 41, Folder 17)
    With maps and index.
  - Nine inch aerial photographs, unlabelled, March, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - New Castle, Maryland (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Dallas, Texas (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Covington County, Mississippi (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Molokai, Hawaii (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Adirondacks (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Lafayette, Louisiana, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Various states in the US (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Aerial photographs and maps of Arecibo, Puerto Rico, 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Negatives of Puerto Rico, 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Aerial photographs of Tortuguero, 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 3-4)
  - Mission 11, Principio Linea, 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Puerto Rico, 1972; 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Ciudad Limon, 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Photographs from roll 28, 1960; 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Unlabelled 10 inch by 10 inch aerials, 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Puerto Rico aerials, 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Brazil 10 inch by 10 inch aerials, 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 11-12)
  - Quebec 10 inch by 10 inch aerials, 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Quebec: General index and photographs, 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 14-15)
  - Quebec railroad, Seven Islands Railroad, QMC line, 1954, 1956; 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Quebec Cartier Railroad, 1950s; 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 49, Folder 1-3)
  - Quebec QCM Railroad Lines 1-4, 1956; 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Quebec QCM Railroad Lines 4-6 (No line 7), 1956; 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Quebec QCM Railroad Lines 8-12, 1956; 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Quebec QCM Railroad Lines 13, 16-21, 1956; 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Quebec QCM Railroad Lines 22, 24-26, 34-35, 1956; 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Alaska 10 by 10 inch aerials, 1954; 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Infrared photographs of Cornell Campus, 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Photographs of Cornell Aerial Photographic Center long-range camera and setup, 1950s; 8.5 x 11 cm, 17 x 12 cm (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Erie Canal and Love Canal: Erie 1, 6, 7, 12, 15 (Box 50, Folder 1-6)
  - Cornell Landfill Analysis photographs, table titles and images (Box 50, Folder 7-9)
    Includes captions and course notes
  - Cornell Landfill Analysis photographs: Ogden, Cortland, Weiland (Box 50, Folder 10-15)
  - Cornell Landfill Analysis photographs: E1, E6, E7, E12, E15 (Box 50, Folder 16-20)
  - Cornell Landfill Analysis photographs: N1, N3, N7, N8, N10, N16, N20 (Box 50, Folder 21-26)
  - Aerial photographs of Niagara (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - Unlabelled aerial photographs, 23.5 x 23.5 cm (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Two rolled color transparencies (Box 49)
  - Color slides for lecture, 1984-1986; 5.1 x 5.1 cm (Box 49, Folder 18-19)
  - New Guinea (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - North Korea tidal flat (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Honolulu, Hawaii (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Photographs for mounting in Landform Report volumes (Box 54)
  - Outwash photographs (Box 54)
- Series VII. Viewers
  - Ta Liang's US Army CF-8 Stereoscope and clipboard (Box 52)
  - Aerial photo viewer, MU-1011
  - Aerial photo viewer, MU-1020